翻译：Iz      Tiogy      红豆包      小布拿拿
校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
更多动画  就在@欧美动漫汉化军团
《开心汉堡店》第五季第十四集
[用我们的喷雾剂]温柔的杀死跳蚤
除虫害公司
得读书  得读书  得读书  得读书
Got to read, got to read, got to read,
得读书  得读书  得读书
got to read, got to read, got to read,
得读书  得读书
got to read, got to read.
我想的完全是相反的东西
I feel the exact opposite way.
你为什么一直重复说这个
Why are you saying that?
读书报告  我在胳膊上写了截止日期
Book report. I wrote the due date on my arm
以防忘记  但那之后
so I would remember, then every day since then,
我每天都愉快地洗了澡  傻死算
I've taken a shower like an idiot.
-截止日期是何时  -明天
- When's it due? - Tomorrow.
你读到哪页了
What page are you on?
封面
The cover.
杰克・伦敦小说  讲述一只狗从文明的人类社会
回到狼群原始生活的过程
《野性的呼唤》
Call of the Wild?
讲的是疯狂的电话销售员吗
Is it about an insane telemarketer?
或者是洗手间的吉恩
Or Gene in the bathroom?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
孩子们
Hey, kids.
鲍勃  之前你灭油火的时候
Oh, Bob, this package came for you earlier
来了个你的包裹
when you were putting out that grease fire.
这就是我讨厌学校的原因
See, that's why I hate school.
我们错过了所有的油火火灾现场
We miss all the grease fires.
我没买东西啊
I wasn't expecting anything.
对了
Oh, yeah.
我想起我订过这个了
I-I remember ordering this.
那是什么东西
What the hell is that?
我买了个遥控版的
I bought a remote control version
《真实的谎言》里的直升飞机
of the helicopter from the movie True Lies,
还配有紧握不放的阿诺德・施瓦辛格和
complete with a clutching Arnold Schwarzenegger
悬在空中的杰米・李・柯蒂斯
and dangling Jamie Lee Curtis.
多漂亮啊
What a beaut.
-你是喝醉后买的吗  -不是
- Were you drunk shopping? - No.
我称之为  "夜晚喝着小酒的购物时光"
I call it "Nighttime shopping, with wine."
我对一个拍品出了价  对  直升飞机
I bid on an auction and, yeah, helicopter.
飞啊  你个混蛋  飞啊
Fly, you bastard, fly!
坚持住  杰米・李  我来救你了
Hold on, Jamie Lee, I gotcha.
《真实的谎言》中反派的扮演者
我要把你从蒂亚・卡雷尔手中救出来
I'll save you from Tia Carrera,
应该是她吧  我忘记情节了
I think. I forget the scene.
老妈何时能玩会啊
Hey, when does Mama get a turn?
我也想救杰米・李
I want to save Jamie Lee.
琳  我刚开始
Lin, I just started.
而且我觉得自己非常擅长玩这个
And I think I'm really good at this.
搞不好可以变成我新的专长
This could be, like, my new thing.
老爸  可不要太酷哦
Dad, you don't want to be, like, too cool.
你好呀  鞋子
Hello, boots.
还每天都这样挂着呢
Hanging like you do every day.
-给我嘛  -天哪  琳
- Give it. - Geez, Lin.
好吧  我让它着陆
All right, let me just bring it in for a landing.
你模仿不了它的  伙计
You can't pull off that look, buddy.
它跟你不一样
It's not you.
缓缓地  缓缓地
Gentle, gentle, and...
亲吻大地吧
kiss the ground.
搞什么飞机
What the hell?
这是什么情况  我让它很完美的着陆了啊
How did that happen? I landed it perfectly.
蒂  蒂
T-T-Ti...
飞得还不错  虽然就这么一次
Well, it had a good run. Of one.
这玩意就是坨垃圾
That thing is a piece of crap.
我得把钱要回来
I'm getting my money back.
蒂  蒂娜
T-Ti-Tina...
也许它还是好的呢  看
Well, maybe it's okay. See?
不行  坏掉了
Oh, no, it's dead.
-松  松  松鼠  -我在读书
- Squi-Squi-Squirrel. - I'm reading
-我在读书  -蒂娜  蒂娜  蒂娜
- I'm reading  - Oh, Tina. Tina! Tina!
多谢  老爸
Thanks, Dad.
我讨厌被鞋砸到脑袋
I hate getting hit on the head by boots.
不客气  蒂娜
You're welcome, Tina.
我们要把它们扔回去吗
Should we throw them back up?
我感觉挺抱歉的
I kind of feel bad.
它们在那里呆了很久了
They've been there for so long.
当心  蒂娜
Look out, Tina!
我刚才  僵住了
I just... froze.
"很有技巧地着陆后"
"And following a skillful landing,
"它却被摔得四分五裂"
"It broke into a million pieces.
"我要求45美金的全额退款外加运费"
Please issue me a full refund of $45 plus shipping."
-发送  -那玩意值45美金
- And send. - That thing was 45 bucks?
外加运费就是
Plus shipping. Which was...
-还是45美金  -那么贵
- also 45 bucks. - The hell?
我是怎么回事
What's wrong with me?
我刚刚目睹了发生的一切
I just watched everything happen!
松鼠  鞋子
The squirrel, the boots!
却什么都没做
And I did nothing!
大家都安静点吧  这样蒂娜才能读书
Hey, let's all be quiet so Tina can read.
-谁在说话  -面对现实吧
- Who said that? - Face it.
我不像电影中的施瓦辛格那般英勇
I'm not heroic like Arnold Schwarzenegger in True Lies!
在《真实的谎言》中扮演施瓦辛格的助手
《罗珊妮》为其参与编剧并客串的情景喜剧
我连《真实的谎言》里
I'm not even Tom Arnold in True Lies!
甚至是《罗珊妮》里的汤姆・阿诺德都比不上
Or even in Roseanne!
好了  吉恩  别为此苦恼
Come on, Gene. Don't worry about it.
那只不过是做父亲的本能
That was just part of being a dad.
你早晚有一天也会有这些直觉的
You'll have those instincts someday.
但要是我永远都没有呢
But what if I never get those instincts?
也许我将来只会成为一个英俊的懦夫
Maybe I'll just grow up to be a very handsome coward!
老爸  你救了蒂娜
Dad, you saved Tina!
你是勇敢的行动派
You're a heroic man of action.
我可以向你学习
I can learn from you.
吉恩  你太夸张了
Gene, I-I think you're blowing this out of proportion.
尽管我在压力下的确是
Though I did react with a certain amount of grace
-比较冷静  -搞什么
- under pressure. - What the hell?!
"抱歉  我们不为失败的着陆退款"
"Sorry, I don't give refunds for crash landings"?!
"坠行员"  好吧  情况有变
"Heliflopter"?! All right, new plan.
网站上有他的电话号码
His number's on the Web site.
我要给这人打电话
I'm calling this guy.
他要行动了
He's doing it!
他是行动派男人
He's man-of-actioning.
我称之为"行男"
Which I call "Mactioning."
你好  是谢尔顿・菲尔兹吗  我是鲍勃
Hello? Is this Sheldon Felds? This is Bob.
就是这样  老爸  教训他一顿
That's it, Dad. Give it to him.
不  不是着陆失败的鲍勃
No, not Bob the crash-lander.
我让它缓缓地着陆的  谢尔顿
It kissed the ground, Sheldon.
缓缓地
Kissed it.
还不如我去爱玩洞商店买呢
Maybe I should've just bought it from The Hobby Hole.
人家那是真正的商店
A real store.
爱玩洞
Hobby Hole!
要不我登门拜访
Well, how about I just come on down
当面要求你退我钱如何
and demand my money back?
是的  包裹上有你的地址
Yeah, your address is right on the package.
那么一会儿见  谢尔顿
So see you soon, Sheldon!
还有  你的字
Oh, and, also, your handwriting is...
-可真不怎么样  -够酷  老爸
- not very good! - Nice one, Dad.
鲍勃  要不这件事就这么算了吧
Bob, don't you think maybe you should just let this go?
你也知道你自己那脾气
You know how you get.
你会开始不停唠叨什么原则问题
You start saying "It's the principle" over and over.
这是原则问题  琳
It's the principle of it, Lin,
-原则问题  -没错  就是这样
- the principle. - Yep, there it is.
等等  你怎么知道我要这么说
Wait, how did you know I was gonna say that?
-我从来没这么说过  -是是是
- I've never said that. - Right. Yeah. Right.
两件只要三美元
这是原则问题  先生
It's the principle of the thing, sir.
这是原则问题
It's the principle!
原则  问题
Prin... ci... ple!
这确实就是原则问题
Oh, well, it is the principle.
得有人坚持为真理说话
And someone's got to stand up for what's right!
周围太吵了
Things are pretty loud,
我还是把手指插到耳朵里吧
so I'm just gonna put my fingers in my ears.
哇  软黏黏的
Whoa, that's waxy!
我是在喊吗
Am I shouting?!
我去了
I'm going over there.
-我也去  -不行  你不能去  吉恩
- I'm going, too! - No, you're not, Gene.
明天还得上课
It's a school night.
我现在就在上课  老妈
This is my school now, Mom,
学习如何成为一个强悍的老爸
the School of Hard Dads!
-请叫我硬汉小爸爸  -是的
- So just call me Li'l Hard Dad! - Yeah!
不  不是那样  但他的确应该来
But, no, not that. But, yes, he should come!
如果吉恩想学做一个行动派
If Gene wants to learn to be a man of action,
我们现在就是在行动
this is taking action!
-好吧  -再见
- Okay. - Bye.
来吧  吉恩  我们去要退款
Come on, Gene. Let's go get our refund!
讨要退款之旅
Refund road trip!
我忘了带钥匙
I forgot my keys!
是的  他忘了  爱咋咋地
Yeah, he did! Deal with it!
-爱咋咋地  -是的
- Deal with it! - Yeah!
看看我们  一个男孩和他的老爸
Look at us, just a boy and his dad,
开车去讨要退款
driving to get a refund.
光是这样说都让我起鸡皮疙瘩了
I got chills just saying it.
吉恩
Well, Gene, it's...
等等  等等  等等  先别说话
Wait, wait, wait, wait! Don't talk yet.
我要录下你说的话  然后反复播放
I want to sample what you say and play it over and over
直到我身体的每个毛孔
until I've got heroic instincts
都散发出英勇的气息
coming out of every orifice of my body.
好吧  跟英勇无关  吉恩
Okay. Uh, it's not about being a hero, Gene.
重要的是做对的的事
It's about doing what's right.
老爹  尽情说教吧
Papa, do preach!
我们的责任
And it is our duty,
整个人类的责任
to mankind, really,
就是为正义而战
to fight for justice.
有人说你得学着放手
Some people say you have to learn to let things go.
你知道放手后会发生什么事吗
Well, you know what happens when you let things go?
会怎么样
What?! What happens?!
你手里的东西就会掉  吉恩
You drop the thing you're holding, Gene.
而现在这个情况下  我手里拿着的
And the thing I'm holding in this situation
-就是这堆破烂  -太棒  听
- is this bag of crap. - Nice! Listen to this.
这是在做正确的事
It's about doing what's right.
我听起来像个大人物
Wow, I sound important.
-很有气势  -能把那声屁响去掉么
- Powerful. - Maybe take out the fart noise?
不要  屁响营造出了你"说得好"
No. It kind of makes you go, like, "Huh, good point"
以及"放得好"的效果
and also, "Good fart."
妈  妈  看我画的
Mom, Mom, look what I drew.
这是长大后的我
It's me when I'm grown up,
和我的猴子希拉一起吃玉米卷
eating tacos with my monkey Sheila.
很棒  宝贝
Great, honey.
-你的书看得怎么样了  蒂娜  -挺好
- How's the reading coming, Tina? - Oh, good.
-真的真的真的挺好  -棒
- Really, really, really good. - Good.
好吧  糟透了
Okay, fine! It's going terrible!
我看得太慢
I'm a slow reader!
一看到逗号就想
And then I get to a comma and I'm like, "Oh, I guess
"这是让我停一停吧  要停多久呢
"They want me to pause, but for how long?
要等多久才能继续看呢"
How do I know when to stop pausing?!"
我一辈子都看不完这本书了
I'm never gonna finish this book!
到时候我就得站在教室里
And I'm gonna have to stand up there
被全班人围观
with the whole class staring at me and my armpits
我胳肢窝会出汗  胸部也会出汗
are gonna sweat and my boobs are gonna sweat
所有的汗汇聚到一起
and all the sweat's gonna meet in the middle
所有人都会知道我没看书了
and everyone's gonna know I didn't read the book!
-谢谢  -蒂娜  亲爱的
- Thank you. - Tina, Tina, honey, listen.
我告诉你个秘密哦
I'm gonna let you in on a little secret, mm-kay?
我上学时  每次做读书报告要看的书
I didn't read any of the books
-我都没看过  - 什么
- I did reports on in school. - What?
对  我从来没看过
Oh, yeah, I've never read the book.
-露易丝  -干嘛  你不也没看过
- Louise! - What? You never read the book.
你应该看才对
Well, I mean, you should read the book.
看总比不看好
It's-it's better to read the book.
我们从来没看过
We never read the book.
你们不看书
How can you do a book report
怎么做的读书报告
if you haven't read the book?
来点表演
You just got to give 'em a little show.
惊艳他们
Pizzazz 'em
这样就没人会注意到你没那啥了
so they don't even notice that you didn't you-know-what.
惊艳  这我倒是蛮有兴趣
Pizzazz, that's up my alley.
有次我作《麦田里捕手》的报告
I once did a presentation on Catcher in the Rye
就只带了个棒球捕手面罩和一块全麦面包
with only a catcher's mask and a loaf of rye bread.
不过那次我没过
Now, that one I failed,
因为我没看封底的内容
'cause I didn't back-cover it.
-封底  -我的个天  妈  让我再扇她一次
Back-cover it? Oh, my God, Mom, Let me slap her again.
别  没事  别上火
No, it's okay. Don't slap her again.
蒂娜还在学
Tina's learning.
蒂娜  你不能从书的封面评价它什么
See, Tina, you can't judge a book by its cover,
但能从封底评价
but you can judge it by its back cover.
我还是没懂
Wait, I don't get it.
我看看  看看
All right, let me see. Let me see here.
一只叫巴克的狗  从家里被偷走后
Dog named Buck, stolen from his home,
被迫成为雪橇犬  生活在
forced to live as a sled dog in the cold,
寒冷偏远的克朗代克地区
unforgiving Klondike region.
我已经有好多想法了
Oh, my gosh, I'm getting so many ideas already!
-编曲  编舞  -编曲
- Musical numbers, choreography... - Musical numbers?
露易丝  你负责道具和服装
Louise, you're on props and costumes!
我负责歌词和舞步
I'm on lyrics and dance steps!
蒂娜  去洗把脸  演出要开始了
Tina, go wash your face! We got a show to do!
谢尔顿・菲尔兹  就是这了
S. Felds. This is it.
-给他们点颜色看看  -谁
- Let's give him hell! - Hello?
-谢尔顿  我是鲍勃  -走开
- Sheldon? It's Bob. - Go away.
-好吧  再见  -吉恩  回来
- Okay, bye. No, Gene, come back.
哦  对  要做强悍老爸
Right, right. Li'l Hard Dad.
谢尔顿  我们不会走的
We're not leaving, Sheldon.
除非你把这破飞机的钱
Not until we get our money back
还给我们
for this defective helicopter!
明智一点  把钱退回来
So do the right thing and give us a refund.
-说的好  -鲍勃  你还是没明白
- Well put. - You don't get it, do you, Bob?
第一次就能把飞机弄毁的"坠行员"
Sheldon Felds doesn't give refunds to heliflopters
我是不会退款的
who crash on their first flight.
不许再叫我"坠行员"
Stop calling me a heliflopter!
虽然它真的很搞笑
We don't care how fun it is to say!
我卖这些小玩意就是为了讨口饭
You see, I only sell those novelty toys to make ends meet.
我的目标是定制真格的遥控直升机
My real passion is customizing serious RC choppers.
这是啥
Well, what is that?
我的四轮机
This is my quad.
我做了些改动
I've made a few modifications
可以用来...戳人
for... poking purposes.
-太蠢了  -戳
- That's dumb. - Poke!
挠痒痒
Tickle, tickle.
-拍  拍  -住手
- Tap, tap. - Stop-stop that.
没打中
Missed me!
-你衣服上有东西  -什么
- Hey, there's something on your shirt. - What?
-打到鼻子了  -停下
- Got your nose! - Quit it!
你是想让我继续戳你呢
So, shall I continue to masterfully poke you,
还是自觉滚回家呢
or do you want to run along home?
我们选后者  再见  先生
The latter! Good day, sir!
-不  我们不走  -好吧
- No, we're not going anywhere. - Okay then!
随你便吧  鲍勃
Suit yourself, Bob!
湿插[一种舔湿手指插进别人耳朵的恶作剧]
Wet Willy!
这怎么就湿了
How is that wet?!
她看上去真不错
Oh, she looks great.
你看上去很不错  亲爱的
You look great, hon.
从来没这么好过
Maybe the best she's ever looked.
转过去一下  看到那尾巴了吗
Give us a twirl. See that tail?
建筑用纸制作
Real construction paper.
-漂亮  -多谢
- Stunning. - Thank you.
摇摇看  亲爱的
Wag it a little honey, will you?
摇一摇
Wag it, wag it.
扭一扭
Shake it, shake it.
不错  好
That a girl. All right,
下面开始《野性的呼唤》读书报告彩排
so let the Call of the Wild book report rehearsal begin!
蒂娜  这是开场曲的歌词
Tina, here's the lyrics for the opening number.
来唱一唱吧  来
Go ahead and sing it! Go on, girl.
好吧
Okay.
*叮铃铃  是谁打来啊*
*Ring, ring. Who's this calling on the phone? *
*是来自"野性"的呼唤  有人在吗*
*It's the Wild, is anybody home?
-歌词不错  -是吧
- Great lyrics, Mom. - I know.
但你要大声点
But you got to belt it, honey.
让你的歌声代替你的眼睛看这本书
Let your voice do the reading that your eyes didn't do.
说的太对
That makes total sense.
你能加上颤音吗
So can you do it with vibrato?
像这样  野性
Like this? Wild, wild!
野
Wild...
不  不太  好
No, that's n... Okay.
唱的时候
You know what, try grabbing
抓住你喉咙前的皮肤
the skin on your throat and moving it around
边唱边动  像这样
while you sing like this. Na...
这样吗
Like this?
不是
No.
让我试试  让我来
Let me try, let me try.
-轻点  轻点  -抱歉
- Gentle! Gentle! - Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
也许我该转去圣马修斯小学
Maybe I should just transfer to St. Mathews.
你以为那些尼姑就不会让你做读书报告了吗
What? You think those nuns won't make you do book reports?
走到哪里都会被强迫看书  蒂娜
People never stop making you read books, Tina.
这是个变态的世界
It's a sick world!
你要学会圆滑应付  相信我
You got to learn how to faux-dazzle it. Trust me.
今晚过后  你再不用看书了
After tonight, you won't ever have to read a book again.
我爱你  老妈
I love you, Mom.
吉恩  虽然我们现在看起来很像
So, Gene, I know it seems like we're hiding
正在垃圾桶里躲谢尔顿的直升机
from Sheldon's helicopter in a Dumpster...
-是的  -但我们只是在重新部署战略
- Very much so. ...but we're actually just r-regrouping.
现在我淡定去地望望风
And now I will calmly check outside...
谢天谢地  终于走了
Oh, thank God. It's gone.
我是说  部署完毕  我们可以出来了
I mean, regroup over. we can get out now.
不必为了我出来
We don't have to get out on my account.
我待得很自在
I'm in my element.
不  我们要去告诉谢尔顿
No, we are going to show Sheldon
我们还在  而且决不放弃
that we're still here and we'll never give up!
那是什么
What's that?
天上游的鱼  这是在《末日迷踪》里
Fish in the sky! This was in Revelations!
柯克・卡梅隆是对的
Kirk Cameron was right!
藏够了吗  鲍勃
You done hiding, Bob?!
我们没有藏  我们在部署战略
We're not hiding, Sheldon! We were regrouping!
我们还是要退钱
And we still want our refund!
游吧我的孩子们  游吧
Swim, my pets. Swim!
你这些行动缓慢的小鱼才吓不到我呢
Your gently floating fish don't scare me, Sheldon!
还挺可爱的
They're actually kind of pretty!
现在有点像在潜水
It's a lot like snorkeling,
虽然我没潜过
which I've never done,
但我觉得我肯定会很喜欢的
but I imagine I would love it!
爸
Dad!
BB枪
You're shooting BBs at me!
打到我的乳头了
That one hit me in the nipple!
那边是好的那个乳头
That's his good nipple!
我的好乳头在流血
My good nipple is bleeding!
结束了吗  鲍勃
Are we done here, Bob?!
你输了  我胜利
You lose, I win! Also,
我烤箱里还有几片冻披萨
I have a couple frozen pizzas in the oven,
所以到此为止
so I'm ready to wrap this up.
-不  还没结束  -还没结束吗
- No! We're not done! - We're not?
不  我们也可以有
No! Two can play the game
会射人的直升机
of having a helicopter that shoots stuff, Gene!
-两个人就行  -你听起来真强硬
- Two can play! - You sound really tough,
即使你捏着你的奶头
even though you're holding your nipples.
我要跟你宣战  谢尔顿
This is war, Sheldon!
欢迎来到爱玩洞
Welcome to The Hobby Hole.
我是泰力  有什么可以帮忙的吗
I'm Terry, how can I help you?
你好  问个奇怪的问题
Hi, weird question.
你们这是不是碰巧有卖
Do you by any chance have any RC helicopters
能实战的遥控直升机
capable of actual warfare?
我们不卖那个的  先生
We don't have anything like that, sir.
跟我来
Follow me.
欢迎来到实战遥控直升机世界
Welcome to the world of RC helicopter warfare.
我就等着这个"哇哦"呢
I was hoping that would get a "Whoa."
我们的实战展馆很隐秘
We have to be pretty discreet about our warfare showroom,
你们懂的  但很酷  有没有
as you can imagine, but neat-o, huh?
空中杀手
"Sky-sassin"?
听起来真残忍
That sounds brutal.
战争就是残忍的
War is brutal.
当然  我们建议你绝对
Of course, we advise you absolutely...
不要瞄准人类
do not aim these at people.
除非你恨他们
Unless you hate them.
现在我要知道我们的敌人是什么样的
Now, I need to know what kind of element we're dealing with here.
是个在网上卖给我直升机的人
Well, it's this guy who sold me a helicopter online,
谢尔顿・菲尔兹
Sheldon Felds.
怎么了
What?
-老兄  -怎么了  泰力
- Oh, man. - What is it, Terry?
最好别惹谢尔顿・菲尔兹
Just stay away from Sheldon Felds.
等等  你认识他吗
Wait, you know him?
他以前在这工作
He used to work here.
-他被炒了  -为什么
- He was fired. - Why?
他吃了冰箱里很多
Let's just say Sheldon ate a lot of food
清清楚楚贴着标签的
out of the fridge in the break room
不属于他的食物
that didn't belong to him and was clearly labeled.
当我和其他的爱玩洞员工
And when me and the rest of the Hobby Hole guys decided
委婉地向他指出这件事时
to gently approach him about it,
他用直升机袭击了我们
he attacked us with helicopters.
你看到这个了吗
You see this?
谢尔顿的一个BB弹嵌在这了
One of Sheldon's BBs got lodged in there.
我再也不能随心所欲地穿短裤了
And now I no longer feel comfortable wearing shorts.
-不是吧  -相信我
- No! - Trust me.
你不想和谢尔顿作对的
You don't want to go up against Sheldon.
我正要和他作对
Well, I am going up against Sheldon.
他跟我们不是一个级别的
He's on a whole other level.
但正义在我这边
But I've got rightness on my side.
正义在你这边
Oh, you've got rightness on your side.
好吧  你厉害
Okay, then you're good.
真的吗  你这么认为吗
Really? You think so?
不  我只是意识到
No, but I just realized...
我干嘛要阻止你
why am I trying to stop you?
我靠这个赚钱呢
I make commission on these.
我来给你装起来
So let's get you all set up.
请看  征服者
Behold the Vanquisher.
她很贵的
Yeah, she's expensive.
-多贵  -300美元
- How expensive? - $300.
没多贵啊
That's not much.
但配上这导弹射程
But with that missile range,
她值这个价
she's worth it.
$300?!
块钱吗
Of money?
不是钱的问题  吉恩
It's not about the money, Gene,
是原则问题
it's about the principle.
是  是原则问题
Yeah, it's about the principle.
泰力  能别起哄吗
Terry, please.
教我怎么操控它
Teach me how to fly it.
其实还是  靠直觉
it's actually pretty, intuitive.
我好像不需要这样手把手教你
Yep, I probably don't need to be holding you like this.
不  有用的
No, it helped.
在我放手之前
You know, before I let you go
-我要祝你好运  -多谢
- good luck out there, buddy. - Thanks.
好吧  多谢惠顾
Okay, well, thanks for coming in.
交给你了
There you go.
老妈的旧踢踏舞鞋  感觉怎么样
Mama's old tap shoes. How do they feel?
有点松  不过我为什么要穿这个
A little loose, but, um, why am I wearing these?
因为没有比踢踏舞更让人入迷的了
Because nothing's more distracting than tap dancing.
只要你一踏脚
When your toes are tapping,
大家就立马觉得你肯定读过书啦
they think the reading must have happened.
现在跟我一起来
Now, follow me!
踢嘞个踏嘞个踏踏踏
And... A tap and a tap and a tap-tap-tap.
踢嘞个踏嘞个踢嘞个踏
And a tap and a tap and a...
踢一下脚呀转一个身
And we're tapping and we're spinning
转一个身呀再踢一下脚呀
and we're spinning and we're tapping.
等下  然后摇起来摇起来
Hold on. So when... And a shimmy tap, a shimmy tap.
等下  我们还在旋转
Wait, hold on. We're still spinning...
摇个腿摇个腿摇摇摇个腿
A scooby tap, a scooby tap. Scoo-Scooby tap.
-伸个腿踢个腿  -等下  什么
- A wiggle tap, a jiggle tap. - Wait. What?
根本没人在看你
Scooba-dooba-doo, and no one's even looking at you,
虽然你啥也没看
what you didn't do, and a-scabba-dooba-scabba-dooba,
读书报告结束后
And the book report's over,
你一定能得A
and you got yourself an "A"!
也许是B-  以我个人经验来看
maybe B-minus, probably, in my experience, you know.
踢踏地怎么样了
Hey. How's the tappin'?
好啊  她简直是个爵士小电钻
Great! She's like a jazzy jackhammer!
-地板  当心了哦  -好吧
- Watch out, floor! - Oh, yeah.
所以  我借了泰迪的独轮手推车
So, I borrowed Teddy's wheelbarrow,
我把它做成狗拉的雪橇车  但条件是
and I made it look like a dogsled, and the only thing is,
他说他也想参加你的读书报告表演
he said he wants to be in your book report,
我告诉他我会试试看
so I told him I'd pull some strings,
让他跑个龙套啥的
get him a small part,
反正  明天他会去学校见你
and anyway, he's gonna meet you at school tomorrow,
你们自己慢慢解决吧  好吗
you can work it out then, okay?
-怎么样  可以吗  -当然可以
- Cool? Is that cool? - Very cool!
你身上绑着独轮车
You could tap with a wheelbarrow
也可以踢踏起来的  对吗亲爱的
tied around you, right, hon?
得站高点
Got to get up higher somehow,
我才能看见他那破阳台
so I can see onto his stupid balcony.
我爬到那屋顶上去就好了
I'll just climb up on that roof!
好的  听起来像个
Sure, that seems like a good idea
不要命的好主意
of something dangerous to do.
-吉恩  你呆下面  -没问题
- Gene, you stay down there. - Yup, no problem.
你回来了
You're back.
是啊  我回来了
Yeah, I'm back,
我还带来了正义  和这个
and I'm armed with righteousness and this!
征服者  我知道了
The Vanquisher. I see.
进去吧  谢尔顿
Yeah, go inside, Sheldon
去拿支票簿吧
to get your checkbook!
喜欢这个吗
Like her?
我叫她征征服者
I call her the Vanquisherer.
我从爱玩洞得来的
I got it from The Hobby Hole.
我去掉了她的无用功能
And then I added the extra "Er"
给她的名字多加了个"征"字
when I customized the crap out of it.
征征服者  真拗口啊
Vanquisherer? That's hard to say.
不  不拗口  你只要第二个征说慢点
No, it's not. You just slow down on the second "Er."
征...征服者吗
Vanquisher-rer?
听着  重点是  他可以征服征服者
Look, the point is, it vanquishes Vanquishers!
我先征服你就不行了
Well, not if I vanquish it first!
你是想来场空战吗
Are you suggesting an air battle?
很好  空战
Perfect! Air battle!
我会让你的宝贝直升机
I'm gonna make your precious helicopter
像你卖给我的垃圾一样粉身碎骨的
look like the piece of crap True Lies one you sold me!
但首先  我能射你奶头一弹吗
But first, can I shoot you with a missile in your nipple?
我很期待呢
I was really excited about it.
让我想想  不行  空战
Let me think. No. Air battle.
-好吧  行  -三  一
- All right, fine! -On three. One...
无意打断
Not to interrupt,
但这真是最好的解决办法吗
but is this the best way to solve this?
-就问问  -是的  -是的
- Just asking. - Yes! - Yes.
二
Two.
三
Three!
我要打败你  谢尔顿
I'm taking you down, Sheldon!
你会后悔那天
You're gonna regret the day you.
天哪  你打中我了  好快
Oh, my God, you just hit me. That was quick.
是时候来致命一击了
Time for the death blow!
不要致命一击
Not the death blow!
什么  泰力
What? Terry?!
我和爱玩洞的伙计们
Me and the Hobby Hole boys
想着你可能需要帮助
thought you could use a little help.
我们查了下库存就立马过来了
We did inventory and then we came right over!
加入战斗吧  兄弟们
Join the battle, brothers!
我的爱好就是吃午饭
My favorite things were eating lunch
和穿短裤  谢尔顿
and wearing shorts, Sheldon,
你把他们都夺走了
and you took it all away!
是时候付出代价了
Now it's time to pay the price!
我没吃你们的美味烤牛肉
I didn't eat your delicious roast beef
和奶酪三明治  泰力
and cheddar sandwich, Terry!
但你的直升机要吃我一击了
But your chopper's gonna eat this!
遥控网击
RC net attack!
这发是为了杰米李
This one's for Jamie Lee!
我的  天啊
Oh, my. Whoa!
不
No!
老爸  你站在台阶上呢
Dad, you're on a ledge!
是的  但我们赢了空战
Yeah, but we won the air battle!
谢尔顿什么表情  吉恩
How's Sheldon's expression, Gene?
他伤心吗  他哭了吗
Is he sad? Is he crying?
不  他在吃东西
No, he's eating something,
还拿了架新飞机
and he's got a new helicopter,
正对着你呢
and it's pointing at you.
现在你屁股上多了只飞镖
And there's a dart in your butt.
爹
Father!
没事的  吉恩
Everything's fine, Gene.
一切都在掌握之中
I've got everything under control.
中标
Gotcha!
-你确定吗  -确定
- Are you sure?! - Yup.
我的屁股
My butt! Hoo!
鲍勃  要不要给你找架梯子
Bob, should we get you a ladder or something?
不用  泰力  快攻击谢尔顿
No, Terry! Take down Sheldon!
爱玩洞的兄弟们  全力出击
Hobby Hole Boys, give him everything you got!
啥  等下  老爸  梯子呢
What? Wait, Dad! What about the ladder?!
感觉你很需要啊
That seems like a pretty good idea.
你现在可站在阳台上呢
I mean, you're on a ledge,
还被插了一屁股飞镖
and you've got a butt full of darts!
是的  但我也有一肚子的原则
Yes, but I also have a butt full of... principles!
所以  你们对付谢尔顿就好
So, yeah, you guys defeat Sheldon,
我稍微动用下我上半身的肌肉
and I'll just work on my upper-body strength,
做几个引体向上  就能上去了
do some pull-ups, and I'll be out of here in no time.
我  一个都做不了
I can't... do even one!
你太伟大了  鲍勃
You're incredible, Bob.
该空中杀手上场了
Time for the... Sky-sassin.
还好我有空中杀手杀手
Luckily, I have my Sky-sassin-assin!
我去拿
I'll go get it.
等着你
Well, I'll wait for you.
你们这些玩家是怎么回事
What is wrong with you hobbyists?!
*这是克朗代克  天气非常冷*
*Up here in the Klondike, it can get pretty cold *
*其它的狗看起来都好生猛*
*The other dogs are looking fierce *
*是时候勇敢起来了*
*So it's time to get bold *
*当人生变得艰难*
*But when life gets tough,*
*你就得以微笑面对*
well, you just got to smile
*你最好响应号召*
*And better answer that phone *
*因为那是野性的呼唤*
*'Cause it's the call of the wild!*
太棒了
Yes!
我太感动了
That moved me.
是的  就像我这样做就好
So, yeah, you just do that.
没人会看出你根本没读书
And no one will even know you didn't read it.
要不我来帮你演
Or I could just do it.
算了算了  还是你演  你演
Yeah, no, no, you should do it. You should do it.
-是你自己的事  你演吧  -没错没错
- It's your thing. You do it. - Right, right, right.
我做不到  我做不到
I can't! I can't do it!
别别别  你可以的
No, no, no, you'll be fine.
-没错  -你只要记住所有步子
- Oh, yeah. - You just remember all the steps.
-你可以的  -所有歌词
- You got those. - Memorize all the lyrics.
-搞定  -别搞砸了就行了
- Done. - And don't mess it up.
-就这么简单  -好吧
- Boom. - Okay!
我  我先去睡觉了
I'm-I'm gonna go to bed.
会没事的
Everything's gonna be fine.
-好吧  -晚安
- Okay. - Uh. Good night!
好吧  睡个美容觉
Yeah, get your beauty sleep.
你的手推车  亲爱的
Oh, your wheelbarrow, hon.
要不要...
You might want to...
她没事的  她可以的
she's fine. She's got this.
我们今天很成功  老妈  很成功
We did good today, Mom. We did good.
-是的  -是的
- We did. - Yeah.
要不要我教你
Hey, you want me to teach you
-怎么逃掉超速罚单  -好耶
- how to get out of a speeding ticket? - Yes!
空中杀手
Sky-sassin!
干掉他泰力  还有我叫不出名字的兄弟们
Destroy him, Terry, and I didn't catch all of your names,
你们也一起干掉他
but you guys destroy him, too!
-他叫万斯  他叫威尔  -嗨
- Oh, that's Vance, and that's Will. - Hi. Hey.
老爸  还记得这个吗
Hey, Dad, remember this?
有人说要学会放手
Some people say you have to learn to let things go.
我知道你对这种说法很不屑
I know you don't agree with them,
但我开始觉得也许"有人"是对的
but I'm starting to think maybe some people are right.
听  这是高音女声版的
Listen, here it is high-pitched like a little girl.
有人说要学会放手
Some people say you have to learn to let things go.
这是超低音野兽咆哮版的
Here it is super, super deep, like a monster.
要学会放手
You have to learn to let things go.
这是加鼓点的
Here it is with a beat under it.
要学会放手
You have to learn to let things go.
不管哪个版本  键盘老爸
No matter how I play it back, Keyboard Dad sounds
听上去都比挂在墙上的老爸明智多了
a lot smarter than Hanging from the Building Dad!
我喜欢加鼓点的
I like the one with the beat.
我今天来是为了
I came here today 'cause I thought
学习怎样成为一个英勇的行动派
I needed to learn to be a heroic man of action.
但看看你们  你们都疯了
But look at you. You're all nuts!
这一切有什么意义  泰力
Is anything worth all of this? I mean, Terry,
很遗憾你不能穿短裤了
I'm sorry you can't wear shorts.
换作我我也崩溃的  但你也没必要这样
I would be devastated myself, but still!
还有  去看下医生吧
Also, just go to a doctor!
有时候  放过那疯子
Maybe sometimes the more heroic thing
也许才是更英勇的做法
is to just let it the freak go!
现在  谁要做那个更大度的人
Now, who's gonna be the bigger man here,
学会放手
and just let it go?!
-我  我不要退款了  -我给你退款
- I-I don't need a refund. - I'll give you your refund.
-不  我先说的  -我先说的
- No, I said it first. - I said it first!
-我更大度  -不  我更大度
- I'm the bigger man. - No, I am!
谢尔顿  抱歉我们在食物的事儿上
Sheldon, I'm sorry we ganged up on you
以多欺少了
about the food thing!
抱歉我把你们的食物都吃了
I'm sorry I ganged up on all your food!
-我原谅你  -谢谢
- Well, I forgive you! - Thank you.
我能回去工作吗
Can I have my job back?
不能  我说了不算
No, you can't. It's not up to me.
还记得罗杰吗  现在他是老大了
Remember Roger? He's in charge of it now.
很难相信吧
Can you believe it?
能去找梯子了不
Can someone just get a ladder already?!
吉恩  你用你的方式
You know, Gene, in your own way,
挽救了今天发生的一切
you kind of ended up saving the day today.
谢天谢地你终于说了
Oh, thank God you finally said it.
一路上我都在想  "我要说吗
The whole car ride, I was, like, "Do I say it?
不  应该让他说
No, he should be the one to say it.
我才不要说"
I'm not gonna say it."
现在我说了  谢谢你
Well, I'm saying it, so, thanks.
今天本来是该我向你学习的
Today started with me wanting to learn from you,
结果演变成你向我学习了
but then you learned from me.
-是不是意味着我成你老爸了  -不是
- Does that make me your dad now? - No.
要不要互换下角色
Do you want to switch for a while?
我可以周一当老爸
I could take Mondays.
我们还是先保持现状吧
Let's keep it like this for now.
好吧  你还是我心中的英雄  老爸
Well, you're still my hero, Dad.
你也是我的英雄  吉恩
You're mine, too, Gene.
我们进去给我的屁股敷点冰吧
Now how about we go inside and ice my butt?
我很好奇还有多少老爸现在
I wonder how many other dads are saying that
也在跟儿子说同样的话  肯定很多
to their sons right now. I bet a lot.
这就是它为什么叫双城记的原因
And that's why it truly was like a tale of two cities.
但我觉得  下次最好还是
But I feel like maybe next time,
写一个城的故事就好
focus on the tale of just one city.
那个城市最好像酸奶店一样
And maybe that city is like a yogurt shop
时髦青年都在那儿工作
where cool teens work.
我也想去那儿工作  谢谢
I want to work there. Thank you.
好的  乔丝玲  蒂娜  该你了
Okay, Jocelyn. Tina, you're up.
嗨  嗨  嗨  各位
Hi. Hi. Hi, everyone.
-讲得不错  乔丝玲  -谢谢
- Good job, Jocelyn. - Thank you.
叮  叮  叮
Ring, ring, ring.
她说啥
What did she just say?
那是野性  的  呼唤
It's the... call of the... wild?
我受不了了  我受不了了
I can't take it! I can't take it!
蒂娜
Well, Tina.
那...
That was, uh...
你们全看到了吗
Did you all see that?
那...
That was...
对  对对不起
I... I'm-I'm sorry.
太棒了
...amazing.
你刚表现出了书里的所有主题
You just embodied all the themes of the book.
原始主义
The primitivism,
《野性的呼唤》主人公  一只最终加入狼群的狗
-巴克回归原始大自然  -对
- Buck's return to his savage nature. - Yeah.
酣畅淋漓地体现  太棒了
The sweating. Great job.
她确实做得很好  太棒了
She was really good. That was really good.
是的  我绝对有读书
Well, I definitely read the book,
她做了点改动  但重要的是她成功了
She changed some things, but, she still nailed it.
太成功了
She totally nailed it.
好了  说出来吧  鲍勃
So... say it, Bob.
-不  -快说
- No. - Say it.
你赢了这周的最佳父母
You win best parent of the week.
耶耶  是我
Yes! Yes! Me!
我还以为是我呢
I thought I won best parent of the week!
等下  你们怎么没在上课
Wait. How did you kids get out of class?
那不重要
Hey, don't worry about it.
我错过了吗
Did I miss it?
蒂娜  我错过了吗
Tina! Did I miss it?
摇摆舞步  摇摆舞步
And a shimmy tap, a shimmy tap.
史酷比舞步  史酷比舞步
A scooby tap, a scooby tap.
根本没人在看你  虽然你啥也没看
and no one's even looking at you, what you didn't do.
扭动舞步  摇动舞步
Wiggle tap and jiggle tap.
根本没人在看你  虽然你啥也没看
and no one's even looking at you, what you didn't do.
读书报告结束后  你一定能得A
The book report's over, and you got yourself an "A"!
也可能是B减  以我个人经验来看
Ah, maybe B-minus, probably, in my experience.